Say, Mom?
What is it, Rio?
Why is our hair black?
We're the only ones.
No one else's is black.
That's probably because your father
and I came from a far-off place.
Oh.
Haruto-san?
Hey, Rio?
Mother...
Are you angry?
H-Haruto-san?
Wait!
What was that?
Spirit Chronicles 2
Rio...
Wait. Rio?
That look on your face is better than before!
Clash
Who'd have imagined there'd be
anyone who could catch up to me?
Though, I did have hopes.
Hey, are you just gonna stay silent?
Say something.
Show your face.
Huh? Who do you think you're ordering around?
You came to save this princess, didn't you?
I shouldn't let him think she
has any value as a hostage.
The one I have business with is you!
Me?
I've been looking for you... Lucius!
And if I am this... Lucius?
What do you plan to do?
I'll kill you.
That's funny! You're pretty funny!
So this is the guy that human-shaped
spirit has a covenant with.
I don't remember him...
but if he's got a grudge against me,
then we must have met before.
Well, it doesn't matter.
How's this?
Is this the face you were hoping for?
Yes, and I've been searching a long time.
You were looking for me to kill me, right?
You seem very calm, considering.
Not at all. I really am
thinking about killing you.
Oh, come on. In that case, you
should show your true self more!
That isn't the look of a man
who's about to kill someone.
I am showing my true self.
I will kill you. That's all there is.
I see. So...
Who are you?
You've met the person you hate,
but you're not gonna give
your name or a little speech?
I told you. I will kill you. That is all.
You're so boring.
But...
Hey! What was that?
It's a dirty trick,
wearing something like that!
A dirty trick? You accuse me of being dirty?
No gaps in his defense, I guess.
Well, it wouldn't be any fun otherwise.
You've long desired to meet face-to-face.
You could let me play a little!
Nice reactions!
But, even though you talked like you
weren't interested in this princess,
it seems she is important to you after all.
Or is it just that you don't want people
getting caught up in your revenge?
Either way... you're too soft!
Aishia!
Behind you!
Aishia, it looks like the monsters
have all focused on you!
It's all right.
Miss Aishia!
It's not a problem.
Come on! Come on!
What's this? The point of
his sword is getting longer?
Is it some kind of spatial magic?
In that case...
You're a pest. You know that?
This guy is finding the precise moments
to attack so he doesn't hurt the girl.
That's more than ordinary skill.
There's no chance I'd forget
someone this strong.
But I don't remember him.
That must means I met him a long
time ago. Back when he was a kid.
Forget it! I'm not doing this!
What I'm saying is, it won't
be any fun fighting like this.
I'm going to kill you.
It doesn't need to be fun.
I think it's time to just reveal your secret.
Unfortunately, I've spawned
so many grudges against me,
I can't remember everyone's faces.
You've sparked my interest.
But for you to know all about me,
and me to know nothing of you...
Well, that's no fun.
It's unfair.
Unfair?
Just who are you?
If you can't remember me,
that tells you what you must have
thought of me as an opponent.
If I'd crossed swords with someone
of your skill, I wouldn't forget!
I'll ask you again. Who are you?
I can't imagine you kidnapped her just
to expose her to danger in this manner.
But this is the best sort of scene, isn't it?
You're pretty calm in the face of all this.
Since I don't remember
you the way you look now,
does that mean we met
when you were just a kid?
I'll take your silence as a yes.
From the cast of your features,
you're not from around here, right?
Still not talking?
Then how about a trade?
I'll let this little princess go for now.
In exchange, you tell me who you are.
Then we'll have a one-on-one fight.
Those terms favor me pretty heavily.
Well, I'm a very kind man, you see?
If you accept the terms,
I'll start by letting the princess go.
All right.
Then our deal is struck!
Stand between us where we can see you.
There may still be monsters around, after all.
Understand?
Good. Now, go.
Sir Ha—
Now, don't go near the princess.
All right, stop there!
As long as she's in sight, I can
use her as a hostage if I need to.
How the situation shakes out
depends on who this guy is.
Please stand a little further back.
All right!
Now, we will change from being
the princess's kidnapper
and the prince come to save her...
to the unsuspecting target of revenge and
the demon come to carry out said revenge.
Now, your part of the bargain. Tell me.
It was over ten years ago.
I was living in the capital
of the Beltrum Kingdom.
Really?
At the time, you were looking
after a certain parent and child.
I see! Those features are from Yagumo!
Your hair is a completely different color!
That's why I didn't remember you! Come on!
Don't glare at me with those scary eyes.
I see now. So, you lived?
Or rather, you stayed alive for me?
That little sniveler, that powerless brat...
It seems you really do remember me.
Yes, I remember. I remember you.
And I've been wanting to see you.
I was hoping for a moment just like this one.
That's why I didn't kill
you when you were a kid!
I'll be back soon. If anyone you
don't know comes, stay inside.
I will!
Rio, it's me. It's Lucius.
Will you open the door?
In this world, there are demons
who masquerade in human skin.
You're one fact smarter now.
I...
I decided... that I would
survive in this world.
I'd survive for this moment.
He stinks.
It's probably best not to get too close.
It'd be bad for your health.
I'm sorry we surprised you
like that. What is your name?
I'm called Celia.
Rio...
Rio? That's an unusual name.
My parents were immigrants.
I see. That's why your hair is black.
We don't have time right now.
I will teach you about od,
and how to use your magic power.
Learn it by remembering this feeling.
H-How to use magic?
Sharpen your senses.
There is light coming from
within your body, isn't there?
Use that light to increase your physical
abilities and make your body stronger.
Take that image and...
I'll untie you right now. Just wait a minute.
P-Please save me!
Won't you please... take me to the castle?
The castle?
You there! Stop!
Lady Christina! Please, wait!
You lied to us, didn't you?!
Please, listen until the very end.
Th-That hurts!
L-Let go, you loathsome thing!
These are Mother and Father's graves.
That's right.
Would it be all right if I paid my respects?
Yes.
I've finally made it here, Mother, Father.
Rio, will you tell us?
Tell us about Ayame and Zen.
Yes.
To cut straight to the conclusion,
both of them have already died.
It is how they died and how they
lived that we would like to hear.
My father died when I was
too young to know him.
My mother was a kind person
who never stopped smiling.
She never showed me her
grief at my father's death.
We were by no means affluent,
but every day was a happy one.
But when I was five, my mother passed away.
When you were five?
How did Ayame die?
If I tell you the truth, it will
be incredibly painful to hear.
Even so, we want to know.
It was for the sake of killing this man...
for this, that I've survived.
I'm overjoyed to see that you grew up
exactly the way I'd envisioned.
Ruining people's lives brings
me the greatest joy, you see?
Now, you've got me
interested. Not bad at all!
Seeing that you're exactly the person
I'd envisioned makes me happy, too.
Should I show some regret and repentance?
Your repentance isn't something I want
to see, nor is it something I seek!
You're draining the thrill
from this, you know?
When someone comes at you with
their emotions, their instincts,
that's what makes crushing them,
subduing them, the most fun!
Oh, right. Zen once told me something.
He said that Ayame was the princess
of some country or other.
What?
Ayame was a good woman.
She sated me for a good long while.
Right up until the moment she died,
she kept trying to protect you.
What are you doing, Master Lucius?!
Please don't kill Rio. I'm begging you.
...were her words.
Rio...
Wait. Rio?
That expression of yours
looks a little better now!
Is that what you want your last words to be?
Yes, that works for me.
It's been ten years, but your
kindly uncle will play with you now!
Come at me.
One-on-one, and—
Spirit Chronicles 2
Go and play by yourself.
What?
It's not possible!
I didn't manage to react? Me?
I couldn't see his movement.
What's his trick?
I can see him. He's slower than before!
What is this unbelievable
physical enhancement magic?
Blast it! His magic just
keeps getting stronger!
Did I lose sight of him at the beginning
because he used that insane
physical strength to move?
This guy's using those
intense attacks over and over,
but his breathing is still even.
What is he, a monster?
Spirit Arts?!
What's wrong? Finished already?
I'm feelin' just fine myself.
He's broken my ribs and ruptured my organs.
I've lost too much blood.
If I don't reattach my arm soon...
When did he get over there?
You're quite the villain.
I'm nothing compared to you.
Let's end this.
Are you sure you shouldn't
be trying to capture me?
I'm sorry to say,
I've received no such order.
You're a stubborn one.
In that case, I'll erase you so that
not a trace remains in this world.
Are you all right?
Y-Yes. Thank you.
I knew it.
You've got to protect the princess... right?
This will put an end to you.
You... What took so long?
What a tremendous blunder.
If only you hadn't given in to that
strange playful side of yours.
I have business with that man.
Unfortunately, I have
business with him as well.
I was here first.
Now, now.
You're trying to kill him, aren't you?
If you do, then I won't be able to
finish my business with him, will I?
So what are you going to do? Run?
Are you going to run in shame too, Lucius?
What?
In another ten years,
I'll cut your right arm off and you
can just keep running. How's that?
You little... Reiss, put me down!
Reiss?
I can't do that.
The moment your physical
enhancement fails, you will die.
You can't be serious! I can still—
We have no choice but to
retreat for the moment.
You think I'll let you escape?
I am quite confident in my skills at
running away and concealing my presence.
Though, I'm not certain
how I'll fare against you.
All one can do is try.
We're going now.
Haruto, watch out above you!
Rio...
Next Time
Toward a Fateful Tomorrow
"Toward a Fateful Tomorrow."
Spirit Chronicles 2
Illustration: Minazuki Futago